

Alian Medina
Software Engineer

alianmc1988@gmail.com +53 5 250 4993



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali an-medina-7a14101a9/

Nationality: Cuban

#### **Skills:**

Problem Solving
Ability to Work in a Team
Ability to Multitask
Customer Service
Fast Learner
Communication Skills
HTML/CSS/JavaScript
Angular CLI
C#

C# NodeJs Express MySQL

MongoDB Git/GitHub

### Languages:

Spanish: Native Speaker English: Native Speaker French: Highly Proficient

#### **Personal Interests**

I love to play the guitar, read, and spend time with friends and family

# **Profile**

Cuban freelance Software Engineer specialized in Web Development using MEAN stack and agile methodologies (SCRUM, XP) to provide the best and the most accurate product to the Client. I have being working in different technological areas such as IT specialist, Network Resources Manager and other no so technical as Tour Program Leader & Guide

I love to work with team mates because it give me the opportunity to help and learn during problem solving, improving my professional and personal skills

# **Employment History**

## **IT Specialist**

Direction of Technologies and Systems, Havana/Cuba (2013-2016)

- Assisted developers and engineers in resolving key issues.
- Collaborated with teams to deliver advancements and solutions

## **Networks & Resources Manager**

French Alliance, Havana/Cuba (2016)

- Providing technical support to the internal network at the school.
- Developing solution to improve the preexistent systems.

### **Tour Program Leader & Guide**

Havanatur S.A, Havana/Cuba (2016-2020)

- Leading groups of tourists around Cuba
- Providing knowledge, assistance, experiences and Cuban Culture

### Freelance Web Developer

Direction of Technologie and Systemes, Havana/Cuba (2020-present day)

 Development of Web Pages and Applications for private business owners, using SCRUM methodologies, and different development tools to create custom-made products (Angular CLI, React, EJS, NgBootstrap, Angular Material, C#, NodeJs, Express, NestJs, MySQL, MongoDB).

Education
Bachelor of Software Engineer, Universidad Politecnica ISPJAE, Habana/Cuba (2009-2014)
Escuela de Altos Estudios de Hoteleria & Turismo, Havana/Cuba (2015)